const essentialsChapter11QuizData = [
  {
    id: "11_1",
    question: "One of the last things you should do before sweeping is roll out drop cloths, runners or other covering from the entry point of the home to your work area. (Page 147)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "False"
  },
  {
    id: "11_2",
    question: "To guard against exposure to creosote and soot, what should you do? (Page 147)",
    options: ["Wear a helmet", "Wear all related PPE", "Turn on a fan", "Hold your breath"],
    answer: "Wear all related PPE"
  },
  {
    id: "11_3",
    question: "As you being your examination with the firebox, what should you do if the screen is easily removable? (Page 147)",
    options: ["Remove it and lean it up against the wall", "Remove it and sit it inside the firebox", "Remove it and sit it on a drop cloth so it doesn't get knocked over", "You should never remove one of those"],
    answer: "Remove it and sit it on a drop cloth so it doesn't get knocked over"
  },
  {
    id: "11_4",
    question: "As you are examining the log grate, if you notice it is excessively warped or worn, it is alright. (Page 147)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "False"
  },
  {
    id: "11_5",
    question: "The log grate should be more more than _________ the firebox width and _________ the firebox depth. (Page 147)",
    options: ["1/2 the width and 1/2 the depth", "2/3 the width and 1/2-2/3 the depth", "1/2-2/3 the width and 1/2 the depth", "1/4-1/2 the width and 1/4-1/2 the depth"],
    answer: "2/3 the width and 1/2-2/3 the depth"
  },
  {
    id: "11_6",
    question: "When it comes to the ash dump door, it should be able to close completely. (Page 147)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "True"
  },
  {
    id: "11_7",
    question: "Should there be gaps in between the facade and the sidewalls of the firebox? (Page 147)",
    options: ["Yes", "No"],
    answer: "No"
  },
  {
    id: "11_8",
    question: "If the fireplace opening has multiple lintels, what should you do? (Page 147)",
    options: ["Note it in documentation", "Ignore them", "Only measure the biggest one", "Cut the smaller one out"],
    answer: "Note it in documentation"
  },
  {
    id: "11_9",
    question: "You are examining the fireplace facade and see smoke staining above the fireplace. What does this mean? (Page 147)",
    options: ["Most likely they had a fire on the hearth extension", "It can signify a potential performance issue and is an indication of a marginal draft situation", "This is normal and the fireplace is working as expected", "They are burning hardwood"],
    answer: "It can signify a potential performance issue and is an indication of a marginal draft situation"
  },
  {
    id: "11_10",
    question: "When looking at the damper frame, what could cause excessive air leakage? (Page 147)",
    options: ["Warped valve plates or frames with mortar in the damper track", "A Majestic Damper", "A Top Damper", "The damper frame is made of cast iron"],
    answer: "Warped valve plates or frames with mortar in the damper track"
  },
  {
    id: "11_11",
    question: "A _________ is a fixed or removable ring, tube, or lining located in the hole where a chimney connector or vent connector passes into a chimney, smoke chamber or flue. (Page 148)",
    options: ["Thimble", "Flue Collar", "Slip Connector", "Snout"],
    answer: "Thimble"
  },
  {
    id: "11_12",
    question: "A metal pie plate thimble cover is safe to use. (Page 148)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "False"
  },
  {
    id: "11_13",
    question: "What is the proper way to repair an open thimble or a thimble covered with a decorative cover? (Page 149)",
    options: ["Close the opening with brick and mortar or an insulated thimble plug", "Remove the decorative cover, sit gravel in the thimble and then replace the decorative cover", "Fill the hole with grout", "Shove a tightly rolled drop cloth or towel in the opening"],
    answer: "Close the opening with brick and mortar or an insulated thimble plug"
  },
  {
    id: "11_14",
    question: "Pie plate covers have the possibility to leak dust and creosote, so you should cover them or plug them to prevent this. (Page 149)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "True"
  },
  {
    id: "11_15",
    question: "_________ are openings usually located near the bottom of the flue or chimney, allowing removal of ashes, dust, creosote and debris. (Page 149)",
    options: ["Cleanouts", "Throats", "Ash Dumps", "Damper Frames"],
    answer: "Cleanouts"
  },
  {
    id: "11_16",
    question: "Cleanout doors are usually tight enough to prevent dust from leaking out, so you don't have to seal them up. (Page 149)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "False"
  },
  {
    id: "11_17",
    question: "Multiple Flue chimneys can occasionally pose a dust migration problem during cleaning. Dust can leak into the house through unprotected adjacent flue openings when one flue is swept. (Page 149)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "True"
  },
  {
    id: "11_18",
    question: "As long as you slowly open the damper, you don't have to have your vacuum running. (Page 150)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "True"
  },
  {
    id: "11_19",
    question: "What could you find on a smoke shelf? (Page 150)",
    options: ["Creosote", "Remains of animals", "Live animals", "Debris dating back to the original construction", "All of these"],
    answer: "All of these"
  },
  {
    id: "11_20",
    question: "After opening the damper and using a flashlight to examine the smoke chamber and flue, if you see any buildup, that indicates _________. (Page 150)",
    options: ["It needs to be swept", "A chimney fire has occurred", "The homeowner hasn't used it", "It is unusable"],
    answer: "It needs to be swept"
  },
  {
    id: "11_21",
    question: "You are still able to do a proper inspection if you leave soot and creosote in the flue. (Page 150)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "False"
  },
  {
    id: "11_22",
    question: "What should you do to the damper if you are sweeping from the top? (Page 150)",
    options: ["Open it fully", "Remove it", "Close it", "Open it halfway"],
    answer: "Close it"
  },
  {
    id: "11_23",
    question: "If sweeping from the top and you have the damper closed, you don't have to worry about dust in the house. (Page 150)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "False"
  },
  {
    id: "11_24",
    question: "What can you do to aid the vacuum? (Page 150)",
    options: ["Wave it around vigorously", "Place a board approximately 12 inches high across the bottom of the fireplace at the opening, or shut one glass door if it is still on", "Cheer it on using positive words of encouragement", "Close the damper"],
    answer: "Place a board approximately 12 inches high across the bottom of the fireplace at the opening, or shut one glass door if it is still on"
  },
  {
    id: "11_25",
    question: "When working with masonry heat-circulating fireplaces, what should you do to the side vents? (Page 151)",
    options: ["Make sure they are open", "Remove them", "Plug them", "Place a fan in front of them"],
    answer: "Plug them"
  },
  {
    id: "11_26",
    question: "Where should you place the vacuum hose? (Page 151)",
    options: ["Wedge it in the damper", "At the front of the firebox", "At the rear of the firebox", "On the hearth extension"],
    answer: "At the rear of the firebox"
  },
  {
    id: "11_27",
    question: "Before sweeping you should assume there is an updraft without checking? (Page 151)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "False"
  },
  {
    id: "11_28",
    question: "Where should you place the vacuum hose? (Page 151)",
    options: ["Wedge it in the damper", "At the front of the firebox", "At the rear of the firebox", "On the hearth extension"],
    answer: "At the rear of the firebox"
  },
  {
    id: "11_29",
    question: "You are getting ready to sweep a chimney and see that is has a downdraft. You can hear an exhaust fan. What should you do? (Page 151)",
    options: ["Ask the owner to shut off any exhaust fans, air handling devices, or ceiling fans", "Nothing because most likely it is in the kitchen or bathroom", "Turn the ceiling fan on in the room that you are working in to combat it", "Nothing and proceed to sweep the chimney"],
    answer: "Ask the owner to shut off any exhaust fans, air handling devices, or ceiling fans"
  },
  {
    id: "11_30",
    question: "To slow air exchanges and isolate your work area from the rest of the home, you can simply shut the doors and windows to the room. (Page 151)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "True"
  },
  {
    id: "11_31",
    question: "Downdrafts are accelerated in homes that have a positive pressure issue. (Page 151)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "False"
  },
  {
    id: "11_32",
    question: "Downdrafts are commonly encountered in _________? (Page 151)",
    options: ["Warm Weather", "Snowy Weather", "Freezing Weather", "Rainy Weather"],
    answer: "Warm Weather"
  },
  {
    id: "11_33",
    question: "In certain conditions it is acceptable to stand on a chimney. (Page 151)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "True"
  },
  {
    id: "11_34",
    question: "Your preliminary exam of the fireplace and chimney will not provide you with enough information to determine if it is best to sweep from above or below. (Page 152)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "False"
  },
  {
    id: "11_35",
    question: "If the chimney is too tall or inaccessible, you should sweep from _________. (Page 152)",
    options: ["Above", "Below"],
    answer: "Below"
  },
  {
    id: "11_36",
    question: "If the chimney is in poor condition, you should sweep from _________. (Page 152)",
    options: ["Above", "Below"],
    answer: "Below"
  },
  {
    id: "11_37",
    question: "If there is a snow storm outside, you should sweep from _________. (Page 152)",
    options: ["Above", "Below"],
    answer: "Below"
  },
  {
    id: "11_38",
    question: "If the chimney is easily accessible, you should sweep from _________. (Page 152)",
    options: ["Above", "Below"],
    answer: "Above"
  },
  {
    id: "11_39",
    question: "If the chimney in in good condition and the weather is fine outside, you should sweep from _________. (Page 152)",
    options: ["Above", "Below"],
    answer: "Above"
  },
  {
    id: "11_40",
    question: "If the chimney has a major downdraft, you should sweep from _________. (Page 152)",
    options: ["Above", "Below"],
    answer: "Below"
  },
  {
    id: "11_41",
    question: "If you notice severely cracked flue tiles, you should sweep from _________. (Page 152)",
    options: ["Above", "Below"],
    answer: "Above"
  },
  {
    id: "11_42",
    question: "Under the guidelines of NFPA 211, a rooftop inspection is required when performing routine sweeping. (Page 152)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "False"
  },
  {
    id: "11_43",
    question: "A _________ is traditionally placed on multiple piers of brick for support. (Page 152)",
    options: ["Metal Chimney Cap", "Single Flue Cap", "Masonry Cover or Slab", "Spark Arrestor"],
    answer: "Masonry Cover or Slab"
  },
  {
    id: "11_44",
    question: "A Masonry Cover or Slab is hindering access from above to sweep, what should you do? (Page 152)",
    options: ["Remove it", "Sweep from inside", "Do your best to sweep from the time", "Skip the sweep entirely"],
    answer: "Sweep from inside"
  },
  {
    id: "11_45",
    question: "A _________ can be secured in a variety of ways. Some use bolts that clamp on to the sides of the tile liner, while others use mortar, masonry nails, and pressure-fitting sleeves inside the flue, construction adhesive, or screws that thread into the top or sides of the chimney. (Page 152)",
    options: ["Metal Chimney Cap", "Single Flue Cap", "Masonry Cover or Slab", "Chimney Crown"],
    answer: "Metal Chimney Cap"
  },
  {
    id: "11_46",
    question: "If you remove a cap to sweep from above, whose responsibility is it to reattach it. (Page 152)",
    options: ["Yours", "The Homeowner's", "Nobody's", "Your assistant"],
    answer: "Yours"
  },
  {
    id: "11_47",
    question: "As you are sweeping, should you stop if you hear falling debris? (Page 153)",
    options: ["Yes", "No"],
    answer: "Yes"
  },
  {
    id: "11_48",
    question: "As you are sweeping, should you stop if you feel a change in friction? (Page 153)",
    options: ["Yes", "No"],
    answer: "Yes"
  },
  {
    id: "11_49",
    question: "As you are sweeping, should you stop if your vacuum changes sound? (Page 153)",
    options: ["Yes", "No"],
    answer: "Yes"
  },
  {
    id: "11_50",
    question: "As you are sweeping, should you stop if you see some dust/soot/creosote? (Page 153)",
    options: ["Yes", "No"],
    answer: "No"
  },
  {
    id: "11_51",
    question: "As you are sweeping, should you stop if hear a flat sound coming from your brush? (Page 153)",
    options: ["Yes", "No"],
    answer: "No"
  },
  {
    id: "11_52",
    question: "As you are sweeping, should you stop if hear a hollow sound coming from your brush? (Page 153)",
    options: ["Yes", "No"],
    answer: "Yes"
  },
  {
    id: "11_53",
    question: "When sweeping, you should sweep the chimney as fast as possible. (Page 153)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "False"
  },
  {
    id: "11_54",
    question: "When sweeping from the bottom, what should you do with the damper plate? (Page 153)",
    options: ["Close it", "Open and Remove it, if possible", "Break it", "Partially open it "],
    answer: "Open and Remove it, if possible"
  },
  {
    id: "11_55",
    question: "Before you sweep you should connect rods to the length you need, then only when you are done should you disconnect them. (Page 154)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "False"
  },
  {
    id: "11_56",
    question: "While you are sweeping, you should attach rods as you being to run out of existing rod length. Then you should disconnect the rods as you pull them out. (Page 154)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "True"
  },
  {
    id: "11_57",
    question: "If you are sweeping a fireplace from the inside, where should you insert your brush? (Page 154)",
    options: ["Through the damper", "Through the Ash dump", "Above the baffle plates", "Through the spark arrestor"],
    answer: "Through the damper"
  },
  {
    id: "11_58",
    question: "When working inside, where should you place tools? (Page 155)",
    options: ["On a drop cloth", "Directly on the floor", "On the floor only if it isn't carpet", "On the hearth extension"],
    answer: "On a drop cloth"
  },
  {
    id: "11_59",
    question: "You should sweep the firebox walls, corners, lintel and throat with a HANDBRUSH. (Page 155)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "True"
  },
  {
    id: "11_60",
    question: "While you are sweeping, you should never _________ (Page 155)",
    options: ["Shut off the vacuum", "Stop to check if flue tile fell", "Sweep the lintel", "Remove the damper if possible"],
    answer: "Shut off the vacuum"
  },
  {
    id: "11_61",
    question: "How should you remove creosote from the smoke shelf? (Page 155)",
    options: ["You should never remove anything from the smoke shelf", "Slowly sweep it into the firebox", "Take a high speed blower and blow it out of the flue", "Turn your vacuum off and begin brushing it so you can hear the amount of buildup moving around"],
    answer: "You should never remove anything from the smoke shelf"
  },
  {
    id: "11_62",
    question: "What happens if you accidentally suck up a hot ember in your vacuum? (Page 155)",
    options: ["It could cause a fire", "Nothing at all", "It will smell good", "It will burn your hand"],
    answer: "It could cause a fire"
  },
  {
    id: "11_63",
    question: "What should you do with ashes that remain in the firebox after you sweep? (Page 155)",
    options: ["Leave it for the homeowner to clean", "Scoop them into a 5 Gallon plastic bucket", "Scoop them into a metal container", "Do not shovel, utilize your vacuum and suck everything up"],
    answer: "Scoop them into a metal container"
  },
  {
    id: "11_64",
    question: "Traditional Sweeping methods will remove hard creosote deposits in most cases. (Page 156)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "False"
  },
  {
    id: "11_65",
    question: "Using chains rotated with a drill and rods is used to remove _________ (Page 156)",
    options: ["Flue Tile", "Hard-Glazed Creosote", "Light Soot", "Bird Nests"],
    answer: "Hard-Glazed Creosote"
  },
  {
    id: "11_66",
    question: "Using chains with a drill and rods can still leave creosote in the corners. (Page 156)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "True"
  },
  {
    id: "11_67",
    question: "Another method of removing Hard-Glazed Creosote, apart from rotary cleaning with chains, is _________. (Page 156)",
    options: ["Using Chemicals", "A Controlled Chimney Fire", "Rotary Cleaning with a Polypropylene Brush", "Hitting it with a hammer"],
    answer: "Using Chemicals"
  },
  {
    id: "11_68",
    question: "What is a potential hazard of using chemicals that require heat to remove creosote? (Page 156)",
    options: ["Chimney Fires", "Improved draft performance", "Lower flue temperatures", "No hazards are associated"],
    answer: "Chimney Fires"
  },
  {
    id: "11_69",
    question: "Homeowners usually know when a chimney fire has occurred. (Page 156)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "False"
  },
  {
    id: "11_70",
    question: "Evidence of a chimney fire event requires a _________ inspection as recommended in NFPA 211. (Page 156)",
    options: ["Level I", "Level II", "Level III", "No Inspection is Required"],
    answer: "Level II"
  },
  {
    id: "11_71",
    question: "If there is a plug in the chimney, usually what side is softer? (Page 157)",
    options: ["Top", "Bottom", "Inside", "The side closer to an offset"],
    answer: "Bottom"
  },
  {
    id: "11_72",
    question: "If you discover a solid plug in the flue, it is best to pound on it with a weight from the top? (Page 157)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "False"
  },
  {
    id: "11_73",
    question: "As a last resort, if all other techniques have failed to clear a plugged flue, what can you do? (Page 157)",
    options: ["Call the fire department", "Just note to the homeowner not to use it anymore", "Breech at the location of the blockage to clean it", "Use a small amount of tannerite"],
    answer: "Breech at the location of the blockage to clean it"
  },
  {
    id: "11_74",
    question: "_________ are required to properly sweep offsets. (Page 158)",
    options: ["Flexible Rods", "Chemical Cleaners", "Long Arms", "Flat Wire Brushes"],
    answer: "Flexible Rods"
  },
  {
    id: "11_75",
    question: "Most liner manufacturers recommend the uses of a _________ or _________ to prevent damage. (Page 159)",
    options: ["Polypropylene Brush or Soft Rotary Cleaning", "Polypropylene Brush or a Steel Brush", "Polypropylene Brush or Chains", "Steel Brush or Soft Rotary Cleaning"],
    answer: "Polypropylene Brush or Soft Rotary Cleaning"
  },
  {
    id: "11_76",
    question: "Gas logs and lighters should have the control key located _________. (Page 159)",
    options: ["On the Outside of the Firebox", "On the actual logs or lighter", "On the Inner Hearth", "In the Smoke Shelf"],
    answer: "On the Outside of the Firebox"
  },
  {
    id: "11_77",
    question: "Vent Free and Vent-less are the 2 types of gas logs a chimney technician will encounter. (Page 159)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "False"
  },
  {
    id: "11_78",
    question: "Vented gas logs must be installed in _________. (Page 159)",
    options: ["A fireplace suitable for burning wood", "The Basement", "A freestanding stove", "In a Hearth Stove"],
    answer: "A fireplace suitable for burning wood"
  },
  {
    id: "11_79",
    question: "When it comes to vented gas logs, a _________ keeps the damper open to prevent dangerous fumes and excessive heat from escaping out the front of the fireplace opening. (Page 159)",
    options: ["Damper Clip", "Damper Blade", "Damper Door Stop", "Damper Kickstand"],
    answer: "Damper Clip"
  },
  {
    id: "11_80",
    question: "Vent-Free Gas Logs can only be installed in a working fireplace. (Page 160)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "False"
  },
  {
    id: "11_81",
    question: "All vent free logs have a safety device called a(n) _________. (Page 160)",
    options: ["Oxygen Depletion Sensor", "Fire Life Saver", "Gas Depletion Sensor", "Dynamic House Alarm"],
    answer: "Oxygen Depletion Sensor"
  },
  {
    id: "11_82",
    question: "The purpose of an ODS is to shut the gas off when the house's oxygen gets below _________. (Page 160)",
    options: ["18%", "20%", "5%", "32%"],
    answer: "18%"
  },
  {
    id: "11_83",
    question: "Every time you sweep a chimney a _________ is required. (Page 159)",
    options: ["Level I", "Level II", "Level III", "Category II"],
    answer: "Level I"
  },
  {
    id: "11_84",
    question: "As a part of the final examination and Level I Inspection, you must make sure the flue is not blocked. (Page 160)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "True"
  },
  {
    id: "11_85",
    question: "As a money saver, if badly rusted or warped fireboxes or fireplace parts are found, it is recommended to just patch them. (Page 161)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "False"
  },
  {
    id: "11_86",
    question: "Should there be any cracks between the outer hearth area and the fireplace inner hearth. (Page 161)",
    options: ["Yes", "No"],
    answer: "No"
  },
  {
    id: "11_87",
    question: "How many sides should the bottom flue tile be supported on? (Page 161)",
    options: ["1", "2", "3", "4"],
    answer: "4"
  },
  {
    id: "11_88",
    question: "What should the bottom flue tile be supported by? (Page 161)",
    options: ["Solid Masonry", "Nails", "Bolts", "Rebar"],
    answer: "Solid Masonry"
  },
  {
    id: "11_89",
    question: "Where should the bottom flue tile be in regards to the smoke chamber. (Page 161)",
    options: ["Should not extend past the inner surface of the smoke chamber", "Must touch the smoke shelf", "Must extend at least 2 inches past the inner surface of the smoke chamber", "Must 1 foot before the inner surface of the smoke chamber"],
    answer: "Should not extend past the inner surface of the smoke chamber"
  },
  {
    id: "11_90",
    question: "How should the smoke chamber be finished to allow the proper flow of gases, direct gases into the flue, and minimize turbulence? (Page 161)",
    options: ["It should be parged smooth", "It should be painted with high temp paint", "It should be visibly corbelled (should look like stair steps)", "It should be angled more than 45Â° from vertical"],
    answer: "It should be parged smooth"
  },
  {
    id: "11_91",
    question: "While finishing up the inspection / sweeping, if the damper was removed you should _________. (Page 162)",
    options: ["Inform the homeowner so they can reinstall it", "Reinstall it and verify it works correctly", "Always replace it with a new one", "Use it to scoop up ashes in the firebox"],
    answer: "Reinstall it and verify it works correctly"
  },
  {
    id: "11_92",
    question: "Before you leave, you should make sure the damper is in what position? (Page 162)",
    options: ["Open", "Closed"],
    answer: "Closed"
  },
  {
    id: "11_93",
    question: "If mortar is missing, and bricks are loose, cracked or damaged, note that the firebox must be _________. (Page 162)",
    options: ["Used less next burning season", "Repaired or Rebuilt", "Used only for small fires", "Swept more frequently"],
    answer: "Repaired or Rebuilt"
  },
  {
    id: "11_94",
    question: "If you find floor joists or wooden forms left in place under the hearth, the fireplace should not be used until they are removed. (Page 162)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "True"
  },
  {
    id: "11_95",
    question: "According to the NFPA 211, chimney and venting systems should be inspected once a year and swept when necessary. (Page 162)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "True"
  },
  {
    id: "11_96",
    question: "After you share the report with the homeowner, if possible have them _________. (Page 163)",
    options: ["Sign the report", "Shake your hand", "Only verbally acknowledge the report", "Prove they know how to use their fireplace"],
    answer: "Sign the report"
  },
];

if (!window.quizRegistry) window.quizRegistry = {};
window.quizRegistry['Chapter 11: Sweeping Masonry Fireplace Chimneys'] = essentialsChapter11QuizData;
